MAYA TILLMAN

Research Study Assistant

CONTACT

Phone (708) 407-6810

Email Mayatillman17@gmail.com

Location Chicago, IL, US

EDUCATION

Integrated Health Studies (B.S.)

University of Illinois at Chicago Chicago, IL | 2021

Psychology

University of Illinois at Chicago Chicago, IL | 2021

Spanish

University of Illinois at Chicago Chicago, IL | 2021

Coding (Certificate)

Northwestern University Coding Bootcamp Chicago, IL | 2022

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Suite

Excel

PowerPoint

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Customer Service

Data collection and analysis

Specimen handling and processing

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Research Study Assistant with exceptional organizational skills and extensive knowledge of laboratory etiquette and policies. Proven experience in biospecimen collection and processing, data entry and analysis, participant engagement, and collaboration with teams. Successful record of participant satisfaction by ensuring regulatory compliance and adherence to practice standards.

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH STUDY ASSISTANT

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY FEINBERG SCHOOL OF MEDICINE | CHICAGO, IL | 2021-PRESENT

Communicated the mission and objectives of the All of Us Research Program (AoURP) to potential participants.

Assisted with electronic informed consent using specialized software.

Conducted physical measurements and blood pressure readings for each participant.

Maintained compliance with standards for patient confidentiality and infection control.

Collected biospecimen samples for laboratory tests.

Processed specimens and prepared each for shipment to testing laboratories.

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO | CHICAGO, IL | 2019 - 2021

Created forms and reports to keep track of department activity.

Managed timelines and helped facilitate department meetings.

Regularly worked with the Business Administrative Associate and reviewed proposals and budget sheets for department expenses.

 $Communicated\ closely\ with\ team\ members\ of\ the\ department.$

Worked closely with the program coordinator for scheduling events and resolving student inquiries Managed the department's official university email and phone line to answer inquiries.

MENTOR

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO | CHICAGO, IL | 2019 - 2021

Provided mentoring services to incoming freshmen, sophomores, and juniors and committed time to each student to ensure a positive and trustworthy relationship.

Organized and planned activities that strengthened academic success and personal development.

Recorded minutes of each meeting.

Reported feedback that related to the individual's progress.

Assisted underclassmen academically and created study plans for each individual.

Served as a positive role model to individuals presenting mental, academic, and physical hardships and provided helpful resources.

MAYATILLMAN

AWARDS

History Student of the Year

Awarded to students who have demonstrated exceptional knowledge and academic success of the subject.

English Student of the Year

Awarded to students who have demonstrated exceptional knowledge and academic success of the subject.

UIC President's Award Scholar

Awarded to students who have demonstrated outstanding academic performance.

Riversville Scholar

Awarded to students who have demonstrated leadership and have a record of serving marginalized communities. Also based on a 3.00 term GPA.

UIC Dean's List

Awarded to students proving exceptional academic performance based on a 3.50/4.00 term GPA.

LANGUAGES

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

SALES ASSOCIATE

UGG | CHICAGO, IL | 2018 - 2021

Accurately processed POS transactions including all purchases and returns.

Promoted consistent sales by providing cordial customer service and knowledgeable assistance.

Trained and mentored new team members on store policies, POS operation, and sales goals.

Organized store displays and aided in product visibility to promote new items.

Aided in the facilitation of inventory and stock management in regards to cycle counts and audits. Applied exceptional standards to all phone inquiries.

USHER

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO | CHICAGO, IL | 2017 - 2018

Assisted with crowd control at special events.

Reported all emergencies and irregularities to the staff.

Controlled the number of people entering the venue.

Maintained order at assigned entrances.

Assured that university rules are observed by the public upon their entering the venue.

TUTOR

EVERGREEN PARK LIBRARY | EVERGREEN PARK, IL | 2014 - 2017

Evaluated students' performance during study sessions and provided feedback to the program's supervisors.

Improved student learning by creating study plans that aided in academic success.

Revised lessons plans and course content to better fit the needs and abilities of the student.

Aided students in subjects such as English, Creative Writing, History, and Science.